ABHISHEK VARSHNEY

DEVELOPER

CONTACT 7014572880 abhishekvarshney222@gmail.com www.abhishekvarshney98.github.io Pune, Maharashtra

SKILLS

- Python
- Cloud Platform AWS, Azure, GCP
- Web ReactJS, NodeJS
- Tools & Tech Airflow, Gitlab, Jenkins
- Problem solving
- · Motivation to learn
- · Analytical mind

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering

JECRC Foundation (Jaipur, Raj)

2017-2021

Aggregate - 75%.

CERTIFICATES

- AWS Developer Associate (DVA-C01)
- Azure Al-900
- Azure AZ-204

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi



PROFILE

Passionate Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in developing Python and web app solutions to client requirements. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services (Systems Engineer)

Aug 2021-Present

Shift Planner Application

 Created Shift Planner Application using React and Node for AMS team members to check the rostering and shift details.

Digital Incident Notification System

 Developed an incident alert system in Python that monitors mail and ServiceNow to notify the AMS Team of impending incidents based on priority.

Scan ID from images

 Developed a python code that scans image and detects ID card, crops the scanned ID card with a confidence percentage and later warps perspective and corrects orientation.

Airflow

Developed airflow DAG for the batch reports. DAG extracts the job statistics
using the AWS S3 bucket integration(boto3). A report is then created and
pushed to Kafka topic which in turn is pulled by Logstash(ELK).

Automations

- Jira Report Automation Created automation using Selenium which reads, processes the Jira timesheet report and generates a final output report with defaulters' names along with the defaulting dates, and sends reports over mail.
- Git release automation Automated git release notes in Jenkins pipeline. This
 automation creates a file with a release notes summary of changes made in
 the project build using the Jenkins plugin and reduces manual efforts spent by
 the team.

Hanu Software Solutions (Cloud Engineer)

Apr 2021- June 2021

Trainings and roles

- Training in Azure and React.
- Certification in Azure.
- Basic tasks given to learn the concepts of cloud and DevOps.